<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Hofstra Data Analysis and Scientific Reasoning</title>
    <link>http://chreliot.github.io/dasr/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Hofstra Data Analysis and Scientific Reasoning</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 17:18:56 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://chreliot.github.io/dasr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Coulda, Woulda, Shoulda: Making Sense of Modal Logic</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/dasr/posts/coulda-woulda-shoulda-making-sense-of-modal-logic/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 18:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/dasr/posts/coulda-woulda-shoulda-making-sense-of-modal-logic/</guid>
      <description>This discussion is a Reasoning Evening hosted by Hofstra&amp;rsquo;s Minor in Data Analysis and Scientific Reasoning.
Abstract: How can we reason about statements like &amp;ldquo;It is possible that Axinn Library has 11 stories&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;It is necessary that Axinn Library has 11 stories&amp;rdquo;? Are these sentences related? If so, how? We&amp;rsquo;ll talk about different rules people are willing to take for granted about statements like these and whether we think these rules make sense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Do Mathematicians Believe?</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/dasr/posts/how-do-mathematicians-believe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 15:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/dasr/posts/how-do-mathematicians-believe/</guid>
      <description>This event is in the 2018–2019 Mathematics Seminar series.
Abstract: Love it or hate it, many people believe that mathematics gives humans access to a kind of truth that is more absolute and universal than other disciplines. If this claim is true, we must ask: what makes the origins and processes of mathematics special and how can our messy, biological brains connect to the absolute? If the claim is false, then what becomes of truth in mathematics?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sign up</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/dasr/signup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2018 14:20:41 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/dasr/signup/</guid>
      <description>Want to join the minor? The best first step is to make a short appointment with the minor&amp;rsquo;s advisor, Christopher Eliot (email), to discuss your interests, make sure you have a sense of the minor&amp;rsquo;s requirements, and answer any other questions you have. Dr. Eliot&amp;rsquo;s office is at 104F Heger Hall. (See Heger Hall on the Hofstra campus map).
If you are ready to fill out the forms to register, you can visit Joanne Herlihy, Senior Assistant in the Philosophy Department.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses for Spring 2019</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/dasr/posts/courses-for-spring-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 10:51:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/dasr/posts/courses-for-spring-2019/</guid>
      <description>At least the following courses counting towards the Minor will be offered. There may be others:
 courses we missed when checking the Bulletin, and courses courses that can count despite not being listed in the Bulletin—especially new offerings and special topics courses.  (Official requirements are in the Bulletin text and substitutions are subject to University approval.)
Category A. Philosophy of Science PHI 152 (QR) Scientific Reasoning There may or may not be a Scientific Method.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Title Change</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/dasr/posts/title-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2018 12:51:45 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/dasr/posts/title-change/</guid>
      <description>MSRDA? MDASR? (Anything but MRSA!)
If you see a couple different versions of our program&amp;rsquo;s name, it&amp;rsquo;s because during 2018–2019 we are reshuffling the program&amp;rsquo;s title. The program will officially be the Minor in Data Analysis and Scientific Reasoning.
With the reversal, we&amp;rsquo;re also working on enhancing the data analysis portion of the program. More developments to come!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Do You Know When You Can Trust Someone? Can Computer Modeling Help?</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/dasr/posts/how-do-you-know-when-you-can-trust-someone-can-computer-modeling-help/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 11:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/dasr/posts/how-do-you-know-when-you-can-trust-someone-can-computer-modeling-help/</guid>
      <description>Students in the course “Coding Evolution of Cooperation” (Philosophy 51 C) have been developing a simulator for Iterated Prisoner&amp;rsquo;s Dilemma games.
If the rewards for &amp;ldquo;cheating&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;cooperating&amp;rdquo; in a Prisoner&amp;rsquo;s Dilemma situation have a certain structure, then agents have an incentive to cooperate over the long term, even though it is always rational to cheat in a single interaction. This structure of rewards is extremely common in the natural world, from the interaction of groupers and wrasse fish to mutual cooperation in human societies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Faculty for the MDASR</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/dasr/faculty/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/dasr/faculty/</guid>
      <description>These Hofstra professors have research interests and offer courses related to scientific reasoning and/or data analysis.
 Christopher Eliot, adviser, Philosophy (faculty profile, personal site) research: philosophy of science, especially biology and ecology teaches: Scientific Reasoning (PHI 152), Symbolic Logic (PHI 154), Philosophy of Science (PHI 161)  Emily E. Barkley-Levenson, Psychology (faculty profile) Anthony Dardis, Philosophy (faculty profile, personal site)  Johanna Franklin, Mathematics (faculty profile, personal site) research: mathematical logic, especially algorithmic randomness teaches: Logic, Sets, and Probability (MATH 045), Mathematical Probability and Statistics 1 and 2 (MATH 137 and MATH 138)  Amy Masnick, Psychology (faculty profile) Roberto Mazzoleni, Economics (faculty profile) Elisabeth Ploran, Psychology (faculty profile) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/dasr/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/dasr/resources/</guid>
      <description> Minoring students might find these resources useful:  The Hofstra LibGuide for Open Science and Data The free, online version of R for Data Science by Hadley Wickham and Garrett Grolemund RStudio, a free, open source, integrated development environment (IDE) for R Entries in the Stanford Encyclopedia of Philosophy:  Scientific Discovery Scientific Method Reproducibility of Scientific Results Experiment in Biology Experiment in Physics Theory and Observation in Science Computer Simulations in Science Prediction versus Accommodation The Problem of Induction Inductive Logic Bayes&amp;rsquo; Theorem Bayesian Epistemology Abduction Confirmation Philosophy of Statistics Interpretations of Probability   </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>